Finding Aid for Kelsey Museum of Archaeology papers 1890-1987
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Institute for Archaeological Research records, 1924-1949; 2.9 linear feet
  - Topical File (arranged alphabetically), 1924-1949
    - Seleucia
      - Yeivin Material, Undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Service des Antiquities, Undated (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Waterman, Leroy and
      - 1931 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - 1932-1935 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Wilson, William, 1929 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Yeivin, Samuel
      - 1928, 1931-1932 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - 1933-1935 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous items (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Near East research minutes book, 1924-1949 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Minutes, 2 folders
      - 1931-1938 (Box 7, Folder 8)
      - 1936-1949 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Thomas Spencer Jerome papers, 1900-1925; 8.5 linear feet
  A small portion of the collection consists of correspondence. Letters written after Jerome's death by friends, colleagues and attorneys, are concerned with the will and estate. The major portion of the collection consists of handwritten and typed manuscripts as well as some notes, most of which were incorporated by John Winter in Aspects of the Study of Roman History, a book published in 1923, nine years after Jerome's death.
  The collection presented several challenges since it consists not only of papers produced by Jerome, but letters and documents about Jerome as well; the papers about Jerome and his estate were considered equally valuable and necessary to preserve the integrity of the collection. Jerome's wishes regarding the posthumous publication of his manuscripts and the establishment of lectureship to further research in classical studies, served as constant thread of reminder and conscience to the trustees assigned to carry out the provisions of the will. Correspondence reflects their careful philosophy not only to adhere to the written will but also to establish a lecture-series which would conform to Jerome's ideas expressed to them when he was alive.
  A significant part of the manuscript collection consisted of news items, articles from periodicals and numerous notes retained on bits and pieces of paper. Jerome had meticulously sorted and filed these items under broad subject headings, then sub-divided them into detailed categories (see 9.7). After consultation with John D'Arms, a member of the Jerome Committee, it was decided to dispose of most of the notes. However, several sets were retained to illustrate Jerome's detailed work habits (see 9.7; 15.1; 15.10). In addition, notes written in manuscript form and all manuscripts whether typed or handwritten were preserved. Further, it was decided to develop and retain a list of the subjects covered in all notes, retained or not, as an illustration of Jerome's meticulous research.
  An index to Jerome's correspondence to Francis W. Kelsey is included in the finding aid for the Francis W. Kelsey papers and can be found in the appendices to this finding aid
  - Section I: Biographical
    - Francis Kelsey. Correspondence., 1910-1914 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Re: Typing the Manuscript. Doris Wylde; William Andrews, 1912-1913 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Vouchers., 1912-1913 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Re: Jerome's work. Letters, clippings, publications., 1910-1912 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Newsclips. (Saved by Jerome), 1905; 1909-1914 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Membership Certificate, Capri Society., 1913 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "Tablet of Tiberius" papers., circa 1912 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - "Tablet of Tiberius" letters., 1912-1913 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - "Tablet of Tiberius" documents., 1912 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - "Tablet of Tiberius" Special Fund. 1915. (Box 1, Folder 10)
      (Includes some letters written in 1912.)
    - Photographs of Jerome. 1912. (Box 1, Folder 11)
      (Correspondence, 1915, 1917)
    - Re: Jerome's death. Genealogy. Biographical sketch., 1914 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Plan of cemetery on Capri., 1915 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - From the Archives of the Freer Library (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Section II: Publication of Jerome Manuscript
    - Correspondence with Publishers
      - George Haven Putnam
        - 1912 (Box 2, Folder 1)
        - 1913 (Box 2, Folder 2)
        - 1914-1915, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 3)
          (Correspondence between Putnam, Francis Kelsey and William Savidge.)
      - Mills and Boon. 1915. (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - Arrangements with John Winter. 1915, 1918. (Box 2, Folder 5)
        (Correspondence between Kelsey and Hobart Hoyt.)
      - Reviews of Roman Memories. Correspondence between Kelsey and Individuals (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - William Savidge.
        - 1912-1914 (Box 2, Folder 7)
        - 1915 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - Delbert J. Haff., 1914 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Hobart B. Hoyt., 1914-1915 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - Morgan Heiskell., 1915 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - Hon. Jay White.1915 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Section III: Jerome Estate
    - Jerome will. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Italian Papers. 1915 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Kelsey Report. Trip to Italy.
      - Financial Statement. A., 1915; 1918 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Listed Vouchers. B., 1915 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Miscellaneous Vouchers. C., 1915 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Duplicates. D., 1915 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Library., 1915 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Extract from deed showing error-in Canone., 1900 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Canone, Monte Dei Morti, Undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Bank Accounts., 1915 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Acquaviva Coppola., 1915 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - American Express Company., 1915 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Alice Tweed Andrews., 1915 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Edith Andrews., 1915 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Dr. Camillo Feo., 1915 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Domanda., 1915 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Dr. Camillo Feo and Henrietta Rupp., 1912-1913; 1915 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Morgan Heiskell., 1914-1915 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - H. B. Hoyt for Union Trust Company., 1915 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - F. Margiotti., 1912; 1915 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - M. Morgano., 1915 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Henrietta Rupp., 1915 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - R. Serena., 1915 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Hon. Jay White., 1914-1915 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Bross Foundation., 1914; 1916 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Section IV: Jerome Lectureship
    - Tentative Plan., 1914-1915 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Formation of Committee; plans for Lectureship., 1914-1915; 1917; 1919 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Action of Regents, etc., 1922 (Box 3, Folder 28)
      (See Kelsey correspondence, Joel Prescott; John B. Pine.)
    - Minutes of Committee., 1922 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Opinion of H.L. Wilgus., 1922 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Jerome Fund., Undated (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Section V: Manuscripts
    - A. Lectures
      - Rome Lectures. 1911.
        - Outline of Lectures delivered in Rome., 1911 (Box 4, Folder 1)
        - Lecture I. Introductory. The Utility of History. (Box 4, Folder 2)
          (Mss. in pencil. pp. 1-52)
        - Lecture II. Material for Roman History: Its Defects. (Box 4, Folder 3)
          (Mss. in pencil. pp. 1-40)
        - Lecture III. Defects in Historical Evidence. Psychology of Thought. (Box 4, Folder 4)
          (Mss. in pencil. pp. 1-39)
        - Lecture IV. Psychology of Testimony. (Box 4, Folder 5)
        - Lecture V. Rhetoric-Roman Education-Mendacity. (Box 4, Folder 6)
          (Mss. in pencil. pp. 1-56)
        - Lecture VI. Reckless Invective, Scandalmongering and Religious Pragmatism. (Box 4, Folder 7)
        - Lecture VII. The Moral Philosophical and Religious Biases. (Box 4, Folder 8)
          (Mss. in pencil. pp. 1-43)
        - Lecture VIII. Tacitus on Tiberius. (Box 4, Folder 9)
          - Mss. in pencil. pp. 1-46
        - Lecture IX. Tacitus on Tiberius, cont. (Box 4, Folder 10)
          (Mss. in pencil. pp. 1-41)
        - Lecture X. Tacitus on Tiberius, concluded. (Box 4, Folder 11)
          (Mss. in pencil. pp. 1-48)
        - Law of Evidence. (Box 5, Folder 1)
          (Apparently a Lecture (XI) at the American School in Rome. Mss. in pencil and typed. pp. 30-36)
        - Lecture XI. The English Common Law and Historical Method. (Box 5, Folder 2)
        - Lecture XII. Race Qualities and Mixture. (Box 5, Folder 3)
          (Mss. in pencil. pp. 1-33)
        - Lecture XII. Alleged Marriage of George V to Miss Seymour. (Box 5, Folder 4)
          (Mss. in pencil and typed. pp. 1-14)
        - Lecture XII. Historical Synthesis-Conclusion. (Box 5, Folder 5)
          (Mss. in pencil. pp. 1-17, incomplete)
      - Capri Lectures., 1912
        - Lecture I. The Emperor Tiberius. (Box 5, Folder 6)
          (Mss. in pencil. pp. 1-66)
        - Lecture I. The Emperor Tiberius. (Box 5, Folder 7)
          (Typed Mss. pp. 1-60)
        - Lecture II. The Emperor Tiberius. (Box 5, Folder 8)
          (Mss. in pencil. pp. 1-72)
        - Lecture II. The Emperor Tiberius. (Box 5, Folder 9)
          (Typed Mss. pp. 1-63)
        - Lecture II. The Emperor Tiberius. (Box 5, Folder 10)
          (Typed Mss. pp. 51-63)
        - Lecture III. The Emperor Tiberius. (Box 5, Folder 11)
          (Mss. in pencil. pp. 1-54)
        - Lecture III. The Emperor Tiberius. (Box 5, Folder 12)
          (Typed Mss. pp. 2-54, incomplete.)
      - The International Congress of Historical Studies London Congress. April 3-9, 1913.
        - Invitations; programs, information., 1913 (Box 6, Folder 1)
        - Society of Historical Studies. List of Members. 1913. (Box 6, Folder 2)
        - Orgy of Tiberius on Capri. (Box 6, Folder 3)
          (1st and 2nd drafts of paper.)
        - Orgy of Tiberius on Capri. (Box 6, Folder 4)
          (Mss. in pencil.)
        - Orgy of Tiberius on Capri. (Box 6, Folder 5)
          (Mss. typed, with copy of letter to President Hutchins.)
        - Paper. "The Orgy of Tiberius on Capri." April 4, 1913. (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - B. Early Manuscripts
      - Malaria. (Box 6, Folder 7)
        (Mss. in pencil. pp. 1-8)
      - Depopulation. (Box 6, Folder 8)
        (Mss. in pencil. pp. 1-4)
      - Plague. (Box 6, Folder 9)
        (Mss. in pencil. pp. 1-7)
      - War. (Box 6, Folder 10)
        (Mss. in pencil. pp. 1-14)
      - Class Differentiation and Urbanism. (Box 6, Folder 11)
        (Mss. in pencil. pp. 1-28)
      - Historical Dialogue. (Box 6, Folder 12)
      - Greek Philosophic Thought--Greek Decay. (Box 6, Folder 13)
      - Letter to The Nation on Municipal Government. (Box 6, Folder 14)
      - Pagan Estimate of Christianity. (Box 6, Folder 15)
        (Mss. notes in pencil.)
      - Latifundia. (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - Criminal Law in America. (Box 7, Folder 2)
        (Mss. in pencil. pp. 1-11)
      - Elimination of the Best in Society. (Box 7, Folder 3)
        (Mss. in pencil. pp. 1-34)
      - Biological Analogy Between Individual and Social Organism. (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - Notes on Lucretius in Relation to Mediaeval and Modern Thought. (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - Synopsis: Wissova: Religion und Kultes der Romer. (Box 7, Folder 6)
        (Typed Mss. pp. 1-12)
      - Notes on Certain Aspects of the Relation Between Emotions and Reason. (Box 7, Folder 7)
        (Typed Mss. pp. 1-15)
      - An Ancient Letter of Invitation to the Neapolitan Bay. (Box 7, Folder 8)
        (Mss. in pencil. pp. 1-17)
    - C. Book Manuscripts
      - 1. "Roman Memories"
        - Fragments of chapters, notes. (Box 7, Folder 9)
          (Mss. in pencil and typed)
        - The Caudine Forks. Chapter VIII. (Box 7, Folder 10)
          (Mss. in pencil and typed. pp. 1-24)
        - "Roman Vice"/"Roman Morals" note.
          (Jerome's larger work, left unfinished, was titled "Roman Vice" but he was persuaded by publisher George Putnam that a less sensational title might be more suitable, so Jerome called his work "Roman Morals." Most manuscripts bearing the title "Roman Vice" were handwritten (except in a few instances). These were arranged together. Items labeled "Roman Morals" were also grouped together. Comparison of the hand written and typed manuscripts in both sections will reveal that the contents are the same.)
      - 2. "Roman Vice"
        - Introduction to the Study of Roman Moral Conditions. Outline. (Box 8, Folder 1)
          (Typed mss. pp. 120-141)
        - Prolegomena to the Study of Roman Vice. Chapter I. Introduction. The Value of History. (Box 8, Folder 2)
          (Mss. in pencil. pp. 1-37)
        - Chapter I. Introductory. The Utility of Roman History. (Box 8, Folder 3)
          (Mss. in pencil and typed. pp. 1-37)
        - Chapter II. Introductory. (continued.) Roman History. (Box 8, Folder 4)
          (Mss. in pencil and typed. pp. 1-56)
        - Chapter IV. The Material for Roman History (Box 8, Folder 5)
          (Mss. in pencil. pp. 1-61)
        - Chapter V. Scurrility, Invective, Scandalmongering and Obscenity. (Box 8, Folder 6)
          (Mss. in pencil and typed. pp. 1-35)
        - Chapter VI. The Satirists and Moralists as Historical Sources. (Box 8, Folder 7)
          (Mss. in pencil and typed. pp. 1-77)
        - Chapter VII. Pious Fraud in the Roman Republic (Box 8, Folder 8)
          (. (Mss. in pencil. pp. 1-28)
        - Chapter VII. B. Religious Skepticism in Republican Times. (Box 9, Folder 1)
        - Chapter VII. C. Pious Fraud in Roman Republican Times. (Box 9, Folder 2)
          (Mss. in pencil. pp. 1-45)
        - Ancient Religious Sentiments As Affecting Veracity. (Box 9, Folder 3)
          (originally numbered VII, corrected.)
        - Chapter VII. The Necessity of Bias. (Box 9, Folder 4)
          (Mss. in pencil. pp. 1-25)
        - Chapter IX. The Empire and Mendacity. (Box 9, Folder 5)
          (Mss. in pencil. pp. 1-55)
        - Chapter IX. Section B. The Senate and the Caesars. (Box 9, Folder 6)
          (Mss. in pencil. pp. 1-44)
        - Chapter IX. (Corrected to XI) Caligula. Notes. (Box 9, Folder 7)
        - Chapter XI. Caligula. (Box 9, Folder 8)
          (Mss. in pencil. pp. 1-84)
        - Chapter XII. Roman Education. (Box 9, Folder 9)
          (Mss. in pencil and typed. pp. 1-21)
        - Chapter XIII. The Cult of Rhetoric. (Box 9, Folder 10)
          (Mss. in pencil and typed. pp. 1-39)
        - Chapter XVIII. The Empire and Religion. (Box 10, Folder 1)
          (Mss. in pencil. pp. 1-21)
        - Chapter XIX. Religious Pragmatism Under the Caesars. (Box 10, Folder 2)
        - Chapter XX. Philosophic Heretics. (Box 10, Folder 3)
          (Mss. in pencil. pp. 1-68)
        - Chapter XXI. Philosophies and Religions. (Box 10, Folder 4)
          (Mss. in pencil. pp. 1-20)
        - Chapter XXII. Stoic Virtues, Saints and Heroes. (Box 10, Folder 5)
          (Mss. in pencil. pp. 1-32)
        - "Nero". (Box 10, Folder 6)
          (Mss. in pencil. pp. 217-236)
        - Claudius; Nero; Reprint from The Classical weekly. re: Tacitus and Tiberius. (Box 10, Folder 7)
        - "The Tacitean Tiberius". A Study in Historiographic Method. (Box 10, Folder 8)
        - "The Tacitean Tiberius". (Box 10, Folder 9)
          (Mss. in pencil. pp. 1-37; pp.17 missing)
        - "The Tacitean Tiberius". Memoranda Regarding the Morals of Tiberius. (Box 10, Folder 10)
        - "The Tacitean Tiberius". Tiberius. 14-37 AD. (Box 10, Folder 11)
          (Mss. in pencil. pp. 78-94)
        - "The Tacitean Tiberius". The Bias in Tacitus. (Box 10, Folder 12)
          (Mss. in pencil. pp. 1-70)
        - "The Tacitean Tiberius". "Copy" for Classical Philology. (Box 10, Folder 13)
          (Mss. typed. pp. 1-36 plus notes)
      - 3. "Roman Morals"
        - Notebooks (Box 3)
          - Outline of work. (Box 11, Folder 1)
          - Misc. notes taken from "Roman Morals." (Box 11, Folder 2)
          - Notes on books read for "Roman Morals." (Box 11, Folder 3)
          - Persius; Martial Petronius; Zosimus; Pliny, Elder. References. (Box 11, Folder 4)
          - Notes taken in reading for "Roman Morals." (Box 11, Folder 5-6)
          - Misc. reading references. (Box 11, Folder 7-8)
          - Walden: Universalities of Ancient Greece. References. (Box 11, Folder 9)
          - Misc. notes. Reading for "Roman Morals." (Box 11, Folder 10-16)
          - Catalogue of Prominent Romans. (Box 11, Folder 17)
          - Magistrates and families. Lists from C.I.L. (Box 11, Folder 18)
          - Consuls. 30 B.C.-235 A.D. (Box 11, Folder 19)
          - Misc. notes. (Box 11, Folder 20)
          - Consuls. 264-31 B.C. (Box 11, Folder 21)
          - Misc. notes for "Roman Morals." (Box 11, Folder 22)
          - Hayden's Dictionary of Dates. 1904. pp. 438-9. Principal British and American authors. (Box 11, Folder 23)
          - Plutarch's Moralia-I,II,III. References. (Box 11, Folder 24)
          - Lucretius, Salvian, Juvenal. References for "Roman Morals." (Box 11, Folder 25)
          - Notes taken in reading for "Roman Morals." (Box 12, Folder 1-2)
          - List of books read in Capri to December 31, 1909. (Box 12, Folder 3)
          - Books read, notes, misc. (Box 12, Folder 4)
          - Catalogue of D. H. Jerome's library. June 1879. (Box 12, Folder 5)
            (Jerome's father)
          - List of books purchased.. Numbered and priced., April 1, 1900-1909 (Box 12, Folder 6)
          - List of books purchased.. Numbered and priced., January 1. 1910-July 1912 (Box 12, Folder 7)
          - Misc. notes of reading for "Roman Morals." (Box 12, Folder 8)
          - 11 Vol. Outline of "Roman Morals." (Box 12, Folder 9)
          - 111 Vol. Outline of "Roman Morals." (Box 12, Folder 10)
          - Data on Roman Names. Bibliographical material. (Box 12, Folder 11)
        - Typed Manuscript
          - Outline. (Box 13, Folder 1)
            (Includes notes by John Winter on Jerome's arrangement of the manuscript.)
          - Unclassified: Apparently a Preliminary Outline of Chapters on Morals. (Box 13, Folder 2)
            (pp. 2-42)
          - Volume I
            - Chapter I. (Box 13, Folder 3)
              (pp. 1-29 plus notes.)
            - Chapter II. Roman History, continued. (Box 13, Folder 4)
            - Chapter III., IV. The Value of Testimony. (Box 13, Folder 5)
            - Chapter IV. VII Notes. (Box 13, Folder 6)
            - Chapter V. Scurrility, Invective, Scandalmongering and Obscenity. (Box 13, Folder 7)
            - Chapter VI. The Satirists and moralists as Historical Sources. (Box 13, Folder 8)
            - Chapter VII. The Necessity of Bias. (Box 13, Folder 9)
            - Chapter XV. The Roman Religion in Relation to Mendacity. (Box 13, Folder 10)
            - Chapter XVI. Roman Scepticism, Insincerity and Simulation. (Box 13, Folder 11)
            - Chapter XVII. Roman Hypocrisy and Pious Fraud. (Box 13, Folder 12)
            - Chapter XVIII. The Empire and Religion. (Box 13, Folder 13)
            - Chapter XIX. Religious Pragmatism Under the Caesars. (Box 13, Folder 14)
            - Chapter XX. Philosophical Heretics. (Box 13, Folder 15)
            - Chapter XXI. Philosophies and Religions. (Box 13, Folder 16)
          - Volume II
            - Chapter I. Political Methods Under the Empire. (Box 13, Folder 17)
            - Chapter II. The Senate and the Caesars. (Box 13, Folder 18)
            - Chapter IV. The Historical Tradition About Caligula. (Box 13, Folder 19)
            - Chapter IV. Caligula. (Box 13, Folder 20)
              (pp. 1-62, incomplete.)
            - Chapter IV. Caligula: Tiberius on Capri. (Box 13, Folder 21)
              (Notes.)
        - Other Material
          - Untitled. (Box 14, Folder 1)
            (Mss. in pencil. pp. 237-399. Missing pp. 273-278; 288)
          - Untitled. (Box 14, Folder 2)
            (Mss. in pencil. pp. 400-501)
          - Outlines. Duplicates. (Box 14, Folder 3)
          - Apparently an Outline or Index to Notes. (Box 14, Folder 4)
            (Mss. in pencil. pp. 1-62; pp. 1-15)
          - Indices. (Box 14, Folder 5)
            (In pencil.)
          - List of Imperial Family. (Box 14, Folder 6)
          - Miscellaneous Notes. (Box 14, Folder 7)
          - Untitled. (Box 14, Folder 8)
            (Mss. in pencil. pp. 134-153)
          - Chapter III. The Trustworthiness of Testimony. (Box 14, Folder 9)
            (Mss. in pencil and typed. pp. 1-65)
          - Misc. Mss. The Censors and Census. (Box 14, Folder 10)
            (Typed mss. pp. 76-97)
          - Misc. Mss. Inheritance of Acquired Character--as Bearing on History. (Box 14, Folder 11)
            (Mss. in pencil. pp. 1-51)
          - Neurasthenia. Notes. (Box 14, Folder 12)
        - Subject Categories Assigned by Jerome
          - Applied Science. (Box 15, Folder 1)
          - Christianity. Persecution of Christianity. (Box 15, Folder 2)
            (Notes)
          - Emotions. (Box 15, Folder 3-4)
          - Emotions. Imagination: Character: Temperament. (Box 15, Folder 5)
          - History of Psychology, Sociology. Progress and Decay. (Box 15, Folder 6)
          - Oriental Religions. Oriental Cults. (Box 15, Folder 7)
            (Mss. notes)
          - Oriental Religions. Judaism-Philosophy. (Box 15, Folder 8)
          - Oriental Religions. Phrygian Religion. General. Egyptian Religion. (Box 15, Folder 9)
          - Population of Ancient Italy. (Box 15, Folder 10)
          - Population of Ancient Italy. Exhaustion of Italy. (Box 15, Folder 11)
            (pp. 1-57, with contents)
          - Population of Ancient Italy. (Box 16, Folder 1)
            (Mss. pp. 1-100)
          - Population of Ancient Italy. (Box 16, Folder 2)
            (Mss. pp. 101-217)
          - Population of Italy. (Box 16, Folder 3)
            (Mss. pp. 218-241)
          - Population of Ancient Italy. (Box 16, Folder 4)
            (Mss. Outline of an Essay)
          - Population of Ancient Italy. Malaria. (Box 16, Folder 5)
            (Typed Mss.)
          - Population of Ancient Italy. (Box 16, Folder 6)
            (Typed Mss. pp. 1-151)
          - Population of Ancient Italy. (Box 16, Folder 7)
            (Mss. in pencil and notes)
          - Population of Ancient Italy. (Box 17, Folder 1)
            (Mss. in pencil. pp. 1-123. Notes.)
          - Population of Ancient Italy. Selected Charts and Notes. (Box 17, Folder 2)
          - Population of Ancient Italy. Hygiene and Population. Reprint. (Box 17, Folder 3)
          - Psychopathies/Psychology. Ideo-motor Activities. (Box 17, Folder 4)
          - Psychopathies/Psychology. Effects of Psychopathies. (Box 17, Folder 5)
          - Psychopathies/Psychology. Psychophysiology-General. (Box 17, Folder 6)
            (Mss. notes, classified.)
          - Psychopathies/Psychology. Neurasthemia: Notes. (Box 17, Folder 7)
          - Psychopathies/Psychology. Functions of the Real. (Box 17, Folder 8)
          - Roman Slavery. (Box 18, Folder 1)
            (Mss. in pencil. pp. 1-110)
          - Roman Slavery. (Box 18, Folder 2)
            (Mss. in pencil. pp. 111-222)
          - Varia. (Box 18, Folder 3)
          - Varia. (Box 18, Folder 4)
            (Notes and mss.)
    - D. Miscellaneous Manuscripts
      - Juvenal's Picture of Roman Society. (Box 19, Folder 1)
        (Mss. in pencil. pp. 1-38 plus notes)
      - Juvenal's Picture of Roman Society. (Box 19, Folder 2)
        (Typed Mss. pp. 1-34 plus notes)
      - Notes on Salvian. (Box 19, Folder 3)
        (Mss. in pencil. pp. 1-262. Omissions)
      - Downfall of Ancient Civilization. (Box 19, Folder 4)
        (Mss. in pencil. pp. 1-200)
- Francis Willey Kelsey papers, 1890-1927; 65.5 linear feet